A Guide to the Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), Laurance S. Rockefeller General Files, 1992-1996, RG 43 FA1325
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), Laurance S. Rockefeller General Files, 1992-1996, RG 43
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
Rockefeller, Mary French
FA1325
137.55 Cubic Feet 105 standard record storage boxes.
Arrangement
Original order created by the Rockefeller family office staff, Room 5600. The records are categorically arranged alphabetically by subject.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Laurance S. Rockefeller papers were donated to the RAC by Mr. Rockefeller's estate in 2009.
Scope and Contents
The Laurance S. Rockefeller General Files were created and maintained by the staff of the Rockefeller family office, Room 5600, Rockefeller Center, New York City. The records predominantly document Laurance S. Rockefeller's 1992-1996 activities in the areas of Art, Conservation, Education, Medicine, Politics, Science, Welfare and Youth Organizations. The records also document a selection of Mary French Rockefeller's charitable giving, 1996-1997.
Biographical / Historical
Laurance Spelman Rockefeller was born on May 26, 1910, in New York City, the fourth of the six children of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. He attended Lincoln School, a progressive coeducational preparatory school connected with Teachers College of Columbia University in New York City, before entering Princeton in 1928. A philosophy major, he graduated from Princeton in 1932 with a B.A. degree in philosophy and went on to two years of graduate study at Harvard Law School.
On August 15, 1934, Laurance Rockefeller married Mary French in the Congregational Church in Woodstock, Vermont. Together they raised three daughters and a son.
During World War II, Laurance Rockefeller served in the Navy (1942-1945), attaining the rank of lieutenant commander.
Laurance Rockefeller pursued a number of successful careers during his lifetime. He was a pioneer in the field of venture capital. He was a leading and influential figure for three decades in the American conservation movement. He led the development of one of the world's foremost cancer care and research facilities, and was both a benefactor and advisor to major educational institutions. And, with great foresight, he combined his personal vision for conservation, recreation and the spiritual needs of individuals to develop internationally acclaimed environmentally-oriented resorts. His many accomplishments have been recognized both nationally and internationally.
In 1935, he began working in the family office in Rockefeller Center. His first duties were to develop his knowledge and understanding of Rockefeller philanthropic activities, conservation projects and business interests, through both study and playing a modest role in their operation. Simultaneously, he developed his own special interest, blending business acumen with the talents of a "gadgeteer," a label he once pinned on himself.
He became well known as an investor of risk capital in young enterprises whose future was based primarily on scientific and technological developments. Over the years his investment interests included the fields of aviation, aerospace, electronics, high temperature physics, composite materials, optics, lasers, data processing, thermionics, instrumentation and nuclear power. Beginning in August 1969, his venture capital investments in these areas were made through a venture capital group, Venrock, formed by members of the Rockefeller family.
In a different area of venture capital, he developed outstanding environmentally oriented resort hotels in Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Hawaii and Vermont, serving as chairman of Rockresorts, Inc., a resort management company which he founded and chaired.
Conservation of the environment and recreational development constituted much of Laurance Rockefeller's philanthropy and public service. His introduction to public service came in 1939 when Governor Herbert H. Lehman of New York appointed him to the Palisades Interstate Park Commission (PIPC). He was president of the PIPC from 1970 to 1977 and continued as a commissioner until his resignation in December 1978. He was an advisor to Presidents Eisenhower, Kennedy, Johnson, Nixon and Ford on matters of environmental conservation and outdoor recreation, and he worked on federal commissions set up to help develop national conservation and environmental policies and programs. In 1958, President Dwight D. Eisenhower appointed him chairman of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission (ORRRC), which charted ways of meeting the nation's outdoor recreation needs through the year 2000. He was a special emissary for President Lyndon Johnson in the effort that led to creation of the National Redwoods Park in California, and he served as chairman of President Nixon's Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality, successor to a similar group which he headed under President Johnson. He played a pivotal role in the creation and development of several national parks including Grand Teton National Park in Wyoming, Virgin Islands National Park on the island of St. John and Marsh, Billings, Rockefeller National Historical Park in Vermont.
He served as a leader of several important nonprofit and philanthropic organizations. He was president and later chairman of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1958-1980) and was a trustee of the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (1960-1982). His first association with Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center in New York City was in 1947; he also served as chairman (1960-1982), overseeing an expansion and modernization of its operations. He was a longtime trustee of the New York Zoological Society (1935-1986) and served as its president (1969-1971) and chairman (1971-1985).
Laurance Rockefeller received many honors for his efforts on behalf of the environment and cancer research and treatment. Among them are the Alfred P. Sloan, Jr. Memorial Award from the American Cancer Society (1969), the Medal of Freedom (1969), Commander (Honorary) of the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire (1971), the Woodrow Wilson Award from Princeton University (1991), the Congressional Gold Medal (1991), the Chairman's Award from the National Geographic Society (1995), the Theodore Roosevelt National Park Medal of Honor (1995), and the Lady Bird Johnson Conservation Award for Lifetime Achievement (1997). In 2003, he became the first person to be made an honorary citizen of the British Virgin Islands in recognition of his many contributions to the area. In December 1959 he received the National Institute of Social Sciences' Gold Medal for distinguished services to humanity, an award previously bestowed upon his grandfather and father. This was the first time in the Institute's history that three generations of a family had been so honored. The citation to Laurance Rockefeller proclaimed him as a "creative organizer of ventures into new fields of human endeavor for the growing aspirations of mankind; [and a] leader in the conservation of natural resources and in the development of the medical and social sciences for the welfare of the individual." In 1967, the National Institute awarded Gold Medals to all five Rockefeller brothers in recognition of their individual and collective services to humanity.
Laurance Rockefeller died on July 11, 2004 at his home in Manhattan.
Prepared by Rockefeller Family and Associates, June 1982 and in 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted in accordance with the 2009 donation of the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual materials (VHS, audio cassettes) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact a RAC archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
File Plan
Former Classification: III 43.
- A - General, 1992-1996; 1
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appeals - Domestic - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Appeals - Foreign - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Applicants - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Arts, 1992-1996; 2
  - Arts - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-13)
  - Bethesda Academy of Performing Arts, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Earth Drama Lab, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Foundation for Hospital Art, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ketchum, Robert Glenn, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln Center - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lincoln Center Theater, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Albert K. Murray Fine Arts Educational Fund, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Royal Academy Trust, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Skystone Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vermont Folk Center, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - World Monument Fund, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dance - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dance - Anima Mundi, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dance - Foundation for the Open Eye, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Films - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Galleries - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Libraries - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Libraries - Bush Presidential Library Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Libraries - Library of Congress, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Libraries - Library of Congress, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Libraries - New York Public Library, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Libraries - The Richard Nixon Library and Birthplace, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Libraries - Jane Stern Community Library, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Memorials - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Museums - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Museums - Buffalo Bill Historical Center, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Museums - Frick Collection, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Museums - Monterey Penninsula Museum of Art, Monterey, CA, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Museums - Museum of the City of New York, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Museums - National Building Museum, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Museums - National Wildlife Art Museum, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Museums - The New Museum of Contemporary Art, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Museums - Rodin Museum, Paris, France, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Museums - San Antonio Museum of Art, San Antonio, TX, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Museums - Shelburne Museum, Shelburne, VT, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Museums - South Street Seaport, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Museums - Storm King Art Center, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Museums - Western Heritage Center, Billings, MT, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Museums - Whitney Museum of American Art, New York City, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Museums - Henry Francis Du Pont Winterthur Museum, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Music - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Music - Gloriae Dei Cantores, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Music - Metropolitan Opera Association, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Music - Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Music - Grand Teton Music Festival, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Paintings - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Paintings - De Claviere d'Hust, Count Bernard, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Poetry - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Publications - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Publications - Ack. Of Books - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Publications - Baile, Gil, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Publications - Cornell, Dr. Judith, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Publications - Jaccaci, August T., 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Publications - Negroponte, Nicholas, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Publications - Oubre, Dr. Alondra, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Material for Reader's Digest Book Forward, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Board of Directors, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Board of Directors - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Finances, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Meetings, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Printed Matter, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Recapitalization, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Publications - Reader's Digest - Three Roses Press, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Publications - Times Mirror, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Restorations - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Restorations - The Admiral Nimitz Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Restorations - The Landmark Trust USA, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Restorations - New York Landmarks Conservancy, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Restorations - Preservation League of New York State, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Sculpture - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Sculpture - Foundation of American Institute for Conservation of Historic-Artistic Works, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Sculpture - Saint Gaudens National Historic Site, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sculpture - Theater - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Aviation, 1992-1996; 3
  - Aviation - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Eastern Airlines - D and O Fund Settlement, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Open in 2029.
- B - General, 1992-1996; 4
  - B - Miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- C - General, 1992-1996; 5
  - C - Miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chappaqquidick, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Civic, 1992-1996; 6
  - Civic - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Billings, Montana, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Partners for Livable Communities, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - People for the American Way, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Chambers of Commerce - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Citizens for a Sound Economy, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - New York City - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - New York City - Battery Park City Authority, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York City - Citizens Committee for New York City, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - New York City - Citizens Union Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - New York City - New York City Police Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New York City - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New York State, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - United States Government, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Clubs, 1992-1996; 7
  - Clubs - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
  - Cosmos Club, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Knickerbocker Club, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - University Club, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 1992-1996; 8
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Arts Center, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Commercial Venture, 1992-1996; 9
  - Commericial Venture - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
  - Banking - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Banking - Chase Manhattan Bank - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Conservation, 1992-1996; 10
  - Conservation - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
  - Citizens Organized for the Protection of the Environment, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Conservation Fund, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hesse-Honegger, Cornelia, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - National Audubon Society, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - National Fish and Wildlife Federation, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - National Wildlife Federation, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Natural Resources Defense Council, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - New York Zoological Society, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - New York Zoological Society - Contributions, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - New York Zoological Society - Meetings, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Open Space Institute, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Roar Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Student Conservation Association, Inc., 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 9-11)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society - Annual Reports, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society - Board of Trustees, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society - Contributions, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Wildlife Conservation Society - Meetings, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - United States Government - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - William Penn Mott, Jr. Memorial Fund, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Park Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Park Foundation - Horace M. Albright Employee Development Fund, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - Acadia National Park, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - Golden Gate National Recreation Area, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - Grand Teton National Park, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - Marsh Billings National Historic Park, 1992-1996 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - United States Government - Department of the Interior - National Park Service - National Parks - Yellowstone National Park, 1992-1996 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - United States Government - Presidents Task Force on the Preservation of Natural Beauty, 1992-1996 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous States - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous States - Hawaii, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous States - Texas - National Wildlife Research Center, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous States - Texas - National Wildlife Research Center - Contribution, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous States - Vermont - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous States - Vermont - River Watch Network, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous States - Vermont - Vermont Land Trust, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous States - Wyoming - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - New York City - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - Board of Trustees - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - Contributions, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - Finances, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - Fundraising, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - New York City - Central Park Conservancy - Meetings, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - New York City - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - New York City - Council on the Environment of New York City, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - New York State - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
  - New York State - Hudson River Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - New York State - New York Parks and Conservation Association, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - New York State, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - New York State - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - New York State - Office of Parks Recreation and Historic Preservation, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - New York State - Pallisades Interstate Park Commission, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - New York State - Taconic State Park Commission, 1987-1996 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
  - New York State - Rockefeller State Park Preserve, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - New York State - Scenic Hudson, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Parks - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Parks - The Parks Council, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Parks - Prospect Park Alliance, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Foreign - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Foreign - World Wildlife Fund - Conservation International, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Recreation - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Recreation - Green Mountain Horse Association, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Defense, 1992-1996; 11
  - Defense - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Freedom Alliance, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Veterans - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- E - General, 1992-1996; 12
  - E - Miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Economics - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Economics - Manhattan Institute, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Education, 1992-1996; 13
  - Education - A - Z, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 2-6)
  - Institute for International Economics, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Association for Human Development and World Affairs, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Center for Partnership Studies, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Center for the Study of Community, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Center for the Study of Community - VHS, VHS (Box 2017:FA1325:001)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further assistance.
  - Classroom, Inc., 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - The Educational Alliance, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Esalem Institute, 1992-1996 (Box 20, Folder 1)